var questions = [
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT an advantage of limiting work in progress?",
        "option1" : "It reduces the potential need to rework a large collection of flawed, partially completed items.",
        "option2": "It helps optimize throughput to make processes work more efficiently.",
        "option3": "It brings bottlenecks in the production process to the surface so they can be identified and resolved.",
        "option4": "It maximizes resource utilization make process work more efficiently.",
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "The relationship between leadership and management in agile methods is:",
        "option1" : "Leadership replaces all aspects of management.",
        "option2": "Leadership is subsidiary to management.",
        "option3": "Management and leadership are used together.",
        "option4": "Management and leadership are incompatible.",
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The core values of XP include:",
        "option1" : "Courage, communication, input",
        "option2": "Simplicity, control, respect",
        "option3": "Feedback, simplicity, communication",
        "option4": "Solutions, feedback, control",
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Agile Manifesto, what is valued more than processes and tools?",
        "option1" : "Customer collaboration",
        "option2": "Individuals and interactions",
        "option3": "Working software",
        "option4": "Responding to change",
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The acronym WIP stands for:",
        "option1": "Worth in performance",
        "option2": "Work in progress",
        "option3": "Waste in process",
        "option4": "Work is  progressing",
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The three pillars of Scrum are:",
        "option1": "Transparency, Communication, Adaptation",
        "option2": "Inspection, Adaptation, Evolution",
        "option3": "$Adaptation, Inspection, Communication",
        "option4": "Transparency, Inspection, Adaptation",
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "On a typical agile team, who has the best insight into task execution?",
        "option1": "Project manager",
        "option2": "Team members",
        "option3": "Scrum Master",
        "option4": "Agile coach",
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following Agile Manifesto values deals most closely with WIP?",
        "option1": "Customer collaboration over contract negotiation",
        "option2": "Css fileIndividuals and interactions over processes and tools",
        "option3": "Working software over comprehensive documentation",
        "option4": "Responding to change over following a plan",
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "What is one of the three questions that are addressed in the daily scrum?",
        "option1": "What have I done since the last daily scrum?",
        "option2": "Why didn’t I get my work done yesterday?",
        "option3": "How will I do my work for today?",
        "option4": "What is my plan for the week?",
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What are three of the seven lean core concepts? ",
        "option1": "Eliminate waste, empower the team, deter decisions",
        "option2": "Build quality in, exterminate waste, optimize learning",
        "option3": "Optimize the whole, defer decisions, amplify learning",
        "option4": "Deliver decisions, amplify the team, evaluate waste",
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "The four primary roles of a servant leader include: ",
      "option1": "Shielding team members from interruptions",
      "option2": "Resolving conflicts",
      "option3": "Determining which stories to include in an iteration",
      "option4": "Assigning tasks to the team members",
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "In Scrum, the definition of done is created with the input of everyone except the: ",
        "option1": "Development team",
        "option2": "Product owner",
        "option3": "ScrumMaster",
        "option4": "Process owner",
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "In the lean approach, which of the following wouldn’t be considered an example of one of the seven forms of waste?",
        "option1": "The handoff between coding and testing",
        "option2": "Testing the code",
        "option3": "Code that is waiting for testing",
        "option4": "Assigned a developer to work on two projects at the same time",
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The XP core practices include:",
        "option1": "Whole team, planning games, small releases",
        "option2": "One team, process game, big releases",
        "option3": "Paired team, planning games, quick releases",
        "option4": "Build team, process game, incremental releases",
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is one of the planned opportunitesfor inspection and adaptation in the Scrum method?",
        "option1": "Velocity review meeting",
        "option2": "Sprint risk meeting",
        "option3": "Daily scrum",
        "option4": "Retrospective planning meeting",
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is an Agile Manifesto value?",
        "option1": "Individuals and interactions over following a plan",
        "option2": "Working software over processes and tools",
        "option3": "Responding to change over comprehensive documentation",
        "option4": "Customer collaboration over contract negotiation",
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "The agile triangle of constraints is said to be inverted from the traditional triangle because it allows:",
        "option1": "Scope and time to vary instead of cost",
        "option2": "Cost and time to vary instead of scope",
        "option3": "Scope and cost to be fixed instead of time",
        "option4": "Scope to vary while time and cost are fixed",
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following Agile Manifesto principles reflects the agile focus on team empowerment?",
        "option1": "Working software is the primary measure of progress.",
        "option2": "Welcome changing requirements, even late in development.",
        "option3": "Simplicity –the art of maximizing the amount of work not done-is essential.",
        "option4": "Build projects around motivated individuals.",
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "The Kanban pull system means that:",
        "option1": "Kanban team members “pull” work from each other, pairing up as needed.",
        "option2": "Each time a work item is completed, the new work item is “pulled” into that stage of the process.",
        "option3": "Iterations are “pulled” into the process as needed to keep the work organized.",
        "option4": "Kanban teams have shorter work queues, which means that the work takes longer to complete (as shown by Little’s Law).",
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following isn’t a core aspect of the agile mindset?",
        "option1": "Welcome change",
        "option2": "Learn through discovery",
        "option3": "Respect the process",
        "option4": "Deliver value continuously",
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a form of frequent verification and validation?",
        "option1": "Pair programming",
        "option2": "Unit testing",
        "option3": "Iteration demos",
        "option4": "Iteration planning",
        "answer": 3
    }
];
